<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Juan A. Ugalde]]></title>
  <link href="http://juanu.github.io/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://juanu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-29T18:17:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://juanu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Juan A. Ugalde]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[juanuu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing and playing around]]></title>
    <link href="http://juanu.github.io/blog/2013/04/28/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-28T01:56:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://juanu.github.io/blog/2013/04/28/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, this is not my first attempt to make a website/blog/some presence in the web, but I think so far seems to be the one that I have developed more quickly into something useful.</p>

<p>I thought about using Wordpress or a similar platform, but I always thought that was a little too much for my purposes. Then I noticed that a lot of people were using static website generators, such as <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> (Based on Ruby) or <a href="http://hyde.github.io/">Hyde</a> (Based on Python). As I'm not expert in Ruby, I was looking into Hyde (not that I'm an expert on Python either, but I have a little more experience), but I was a little dissapointed with the lack of documentation. Then I found this: <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>, which is a framework based on Jekyll, which already provides the necessary basic structure (HTML, CSS, Javascript) files to start with a website. I decided to give a try, so I could start building a site/blog, and learn about the details during the process.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Some of the reasons that made static site generators attractive were:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>"Simplicity": I put this in quotes, because it took me a while to figure out the programs, dependencies, and things that I needed to be able to run. But, once that everything was running, it just takes a few minutes of buliding and the website is ready!</p></li>
<li><p>More accessible: I don't know the exact word to refer to this, but for me, is much easier to write a quick blog post using Markdown (a lightweight markup language) in a text editor, than going to Wordpress, login in, start writing, etc. I see this as a process similar to using Latex, where you are not worried about the design of the text (like in Word), but more about the content itself. Of course, I'm saying this right now, but let's see if this translate into more writing!</p></li>
<li><p>Learning: I think it was time to start learning some serious HTML, CSS and even Javascript!</p></li>
</ul>


<p>So, after a few days, the experience has been interesting, and I'll see how this works in the future. Feel free to ask any questions or comments!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
